<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stand Against Spying</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://standagainstspying.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://standagainstspying.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>New Scorecard Rates How Your Representative Stands on NSA Spying</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freedomworks.org/content/new-scorecard-see-how-your-representative-stands-nsa-spying&quot;&gt;FreedomWorks.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does your representative stand on NSA spying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FreedomWorks has joined with groups across the political spectrum to bring you a scorecard that tracks your representative’s voting and co-sponsorship history on NSA reform bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://standagainstspying.org?r=fw&quot;&gt;StandAgainstSpying.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Thanks to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for leading the effort! P.S. did you see their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/diverse-groups-fly-airship-over-nsas-utah-data-center-protest-illegal-internet-spying&quot;&gt;airship flying&lt;/a&gt; over the NSA's Utah data center to protest illegal spying?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quick and easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all are busy and cannot always pay close attention to what’s happening in Congress. That's why this surveillance scorecard is such a great tool. This website is a one stop shop to find out if your representative is standing up for civil liberties— or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website allows you to hold your representative accountable by quickly looking up their scores (A through F) and then sharing their scores on Twitter. Scores can be tweeted directly to members of Congress with a note of encouragement or disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://supporters.eff.org/sites/default/files/JustinAmashtweetNSA.png&quot; alt=&quot;JustinAmashTweet2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://supporters.eff.org/sites/default/files/mikerogerstweetNSA.png&quot; alt=&quot;MikeRogersTweet2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer not to use social media, you can voice your concerns about domestic spying by signing onto an &lt;a href=&quot;https://standagainstspying.org/#letter-signup&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; to President Obama urging him to take immediate steps to end the mass spying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the website is to spread awareness of the surveillance debates happening in Congress and put pressure on elected representatives to support meaningful surveillance reform. The scorecard does not factor in any public statements on NSA reform but rather only rates &lt;a href=&quot;https://standagainstspying.org/methodology/&quot;&gt;based&lt;/a&gt; on votes and co-sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting aspects of the website is the list of organizations advocating for an end to mass surveillance. The partnering organizations range from Greenpeace and Demand Progress to the Libertarian Party and FreedomWorks. We don’t always agree with these organizations, but we all agree that it’s time to outlaw mass surveillance. Thankfully, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/10/polls-continue-show-majority-americans-against-nsa-spying&quot;&gt;majority&lt;/a&gt; of Americans are also against NSA spying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://standagainstspying.org?r=fw&quot;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt; and let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 17:40:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>https://standagainstspying.org/2014/06/28/new-scorecard-rates-your-representative-stands-on-nsa-spying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://standagainstspying.org/2014/06/28/new-scorecard-rates-your-representative-stands-on-nsa-spying/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diverse Groups Fly Airship Over NSA’s Utah Data Center to Protest Illegal Spying</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Flight Promotes StandAgainstSpying.org, New Site Calling on Congress to Act&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;      
  &lt;div class=&quot;views-field views-field-field-image&quot;&gt;        &lt;div class=&quot;field-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.1108.jpg&quot; class=&quot;views-ajax-processed-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/styles/large/public/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.1108.jpg?itok=yuhfYda4&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;327&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Greenpeace, EFF and the Tenth Amendment Center fly and airship over the NSA data center in Utah. Credit: Greenpeace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;            &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bluffdale, UT - The environmental campaigning group Greenpeace, digital rights watchdog Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) and the Tenth Amendment Center (TAC) joined forces today to fly an airship over the NSA's data center in Utah to protest the government's illegal mass surveillance program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace flew its 135-foot-long thermal airship over the Bluffdale, UT, data center early Friday morning, carrying the message: &quot;NSA Illegal Spying Below&quot; along with a link steering people to a new web site, &lt;a href=&quot;http://standagainstspying.org/&quot;&gt;StandAgainstSpying.org&lt;/a&gt;, which the three groups launched with the support of a separate, diverse coalition of over 20 grassroots advocacy groups and Internet companies. The site grades members of Congress on what they have done, or often not done, to rein in the NSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Rights rise or fall together,&quot; Greenpeace Senior IT Campaigner Gary Cook said. &quot;Greenpeace has learned firsthand that people cannot protect their right to clean air and water if our civil rights – including the right to free association and the right to be free of unreasonable searches – are stripped away.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The public needs to be brought into the Congressional debate around surveillance reform happening right now,&quot; EFF Activism Director Rainey Reitman said. &quot;We're flying an airship over the Utah data center, which has come to symbolize the NSA's collect-it-all approach to surveillance, and demanding an end to the mass spying. It's time for bold action in defense of our privacy.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our right to privacy is not a partisan issue. It's a human rights issue,&quot; said Michael Boldin, executive director and founder of the Tenth Amendment Center. &quot;This coalition gives great hope for the future because it shows that people across the political spectrum can set aside differences to work together for common cause.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace is a co-plaintiff on a lawsuit filed against the NSA by a broad coalition of membership and political advocacy organizations, represented by EFF, for violating their First Amendment right of association by illegally collecting their call records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contacts:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rainey Reitman&lt;br /&gt;
   Activism Director&lt;br /&gt;
   Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rainey@eff.org&quot;&gt;rainey@eff.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Pomerantz&lt;br /&gt;
   Greenpeace&lt;br /&gt;
   david.pomerantz@greenpeace.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Stepanian&lt;br /&gt;
   Fitzgibbon Media&lt;br /&gt;
   andy@fitzgibbonmedia.com&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rainey@eff.org&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos of the airship flight are available here under a Creative Commons Attribution license. Please attribute to Greenpeace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;      
  &lt;div class=&quot;views-field views-field-field-image&quot;&gt;        &lt;div class=&quot;field-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.1051.jpg&quot; class=&quot;views-ajax-processed-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/styles/large/public/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.1051.jpg?itok=uqSMTyG_&quot; width=&quot;363&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Greenpeace, EFF and the Tenth Amendment Center fly and airship over the NSA data center in Utah. Credit: Greenpeace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;            &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;      
  &lt;div class=&quot;views-field views-field-field-image&quot;&gt;        &lt;div class=&quot;field-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.2072.jpg&quot; class=&quot;views-ajax-processed-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/styles/large/public/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.2072.jpg?itok=chMxHH2U&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;279&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Greenpeace, EFF and the Tenth Amendment Center fly and airship over the NSA data center in Utah. Credit: Greenpeace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;views-field views-field-field-image&quot;&gt;        &lt;div class=&quot;field-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.1137.jpg&quot; class=&quot;views-ajax-processed-processed&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/styles/large/public/2014/06/27/8.14.68_utah_airship_flight.1137.jpg?itok=F2ZMemzK&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Greenpeace, EFF and the Tenth Amendment Center fly and airship over the NSA data center in Utah. Credit: Greenpeace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 22:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>https://standagainstspying.org/2014/06/27/diverse-groups-fly-airship-over-nsa-utah-data-center-to-protest-illegal-spying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://standagainstspying.org/2014/06/27/diverse-groups-fly-airship-over-nsa-utah-data-center-to-protest-illegal-spying/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Congressional Scorecard on Mass Surveillance: StandAgainstSpying.org Launches to Encourage NSA Reform</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;June 27, 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T3&quot;&gt;Congressional Scorecard on Mass Surveillance: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T4&quot;&gt;StandAgainstSpying.org Launches to Encourage NSA Reform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;Diverse Coalition Reveals &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;Lawmakers Who Aced, Failed and Were Missing in the Debate Over Mass Spying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO, CA - A coalition of 21 organizations from across the political spectrum today launched StandAgainstSpying.org, an interactive website that grades members of Congress on what they have done, or often not done, to rein in the NSA.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;Led by the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF), the Sunlight Foundation and Greenpeace, the coalition aims to inspire constituents to hold their elected officials accountable on mass surveillance reform, as well as give lawmakers the opportunity to improve their positions. Using a report card-style format, the grading criteria included whether the legislator was a sponsor of the USA FREEDOM Act or, in the case of the House of Representatives, voted for the “Amash Amendment” to defund NSA mass surveillance. Legislators had multiple avenues for receiving high marks. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;Of the 100 senators and 433 representatives included, 241 members (45 percent) received “A” grades.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;However, 188 members (35 percent) flunked the scorecard, while another 77 members (14 percent) received question marks for taking no measurable action.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;Website visitors can enter their zip codes to look up their congressional members’ scores. They then are encouraged to tweet directly at their members of Congress, thanking them for defending privacy or asking them to do more in the fight against mass spying. Additionally, all visitors can sign an open letter to President Barack Obama urging him to end the mass surveillance programs immediately, without waiting for Congress to act.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;“We must hold members of Congress accountable by making clear to the public who in Congress is standing up for surveillance reform, who is acting as a roadblock, and who is failing to take a stand,” EFF Activism Director Rainey Reitman said. “More Americans than ever now think the NSA has gone too far. The American people—and frankly people all over the world—can't wait any longer for Congress to rein in the NSA.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;EFF built StandAgainstSpying.org after analyzing the key NSA reform bills in Congress and weighting the prominent proposals on the degree to which they would end mass data collection. Sunlight Foundation technologists populated the site with data from its repository of Congressional actions. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Standard&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;&quot;Just as the Internet has become an avenue for surveillance, it is also a mechanism for the public to hold the government accountable for its unchecked secrecy,” said John Wonderlich, policy &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;director at the nonpartisan Sunlight Foundation. “People care about secrecy and state power and are willing to stand up and demand reform.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Standard&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;More than &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;18 groups and companies with diverse interests joined Greenpeace, EFF, Tenth Amendment Center (TAC) and Sunlight Foundation as partners in launching StandAgainstSpying.org, including &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;Association of Alternative Newsmedia, Bill of Rights Defense Commmittee, Demand Progress, Fight for the Future,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;FreedomWorks, Free Press Action Fund,  Freedom of the Press Foundation, Libertarian Party, Liberty Coalition, Open Media, PEN America, reddit, Restore the Fourth, Taskforce.is, TechFreedom and ThoughtWorks. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;The launch of the scorecard also coincided with a joint campaign by Greenpeace, EFF and TAC to fly an airship over the NSA data center in Bluffdale, UT, which carried a sign that read “NSA Illegal Spying Below” with a link to StandAgainstSpying.org.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;###&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 17:40:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>https://standagainstspying.org/2014/06/27/welcome-to-stand-against-spying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://standagainstspying.org/2014/06/27/welcome-to-stand-against-spying/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
